<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://jianhao1991.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://jianhao1991.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-10-06T20:03:48+00:00</updated><id>https://jianhao1991.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Jianhao Zhang | Research Scientist | CIRES at University of Colorado Boulder &amp; NOAA CSL. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Radiative Impact of the IMO2020 Shipping Fuel Regulation</title><link href="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2025/IMO/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radiative Impact of the IMO2020 Shipping Fuel Regulation"/><published>2025-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2025/IMO</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2025/IMO/"><![CDATA[<p>Ship tracks—bright, linear clouds trailing ocean-going ships—are striking manifestations of cloud adjustment in response to inadvertent aerosol perturbations from shipping emissions. Their radiative characteristics, contrasted with surrounding unperturbed scenes, offer invaluable insights into aerosol–cloud–radiation interactions. In this work, I trained ensembles of neural networks to examine how reduced pollution from shipping affects cloud properties and climate. The results reveal that while the IMO2020 regulation brings significant environmental and public health benefits, it also produces a global warming effect of approximately 0.1 W m<sup>−2</sup>, equivalent to about 3.5 years of CO<sub>2</sub> warming. We concluded that even this substantial, abrupt radiative forcing is challenging to detect, underscoring the difficulty of observing real-world cloud adjustments against natural cloud variability.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset=" /assets/img/IMO_poster-480.webp 480w, /assets/img/IMO_poster-800.webp 800w, /assets/img/IMO_poster-1400.webp 1400w, " sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/IMO_poster.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <hr/> <blockquote> <p>This study raises concerns about accelerated warming associated with future emission regulations and the detectability of Marine Cloud Brightening (MCB) as a geoengineering proposal.</p> </blockquote> <h4 id="related-publications">Related Publications</h4> <ul> <li><strong>J. Zhang</strong>, Y.-S. Chen, E. Gryspeerdt, T. Yamaguchi, and G. Feingold (2025): Radiative forcing from the 2020 shipping fuel regulation is large but hard to detect. <em>Commun. Earth Environ.</em>, 6(18), 1–11. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s43247-024-01911-9"><em>doi:10.1038/s43247-024-01911-9</em></a></li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="research"/><category term="Machine-Learning"/><category term="Neural-Networks"/><category term="Marine-Cloud-Brightening"/><category term="Detectability"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using ensembles of neural networks trained on satellite and reanalysis to quantify the .]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mcb</title><link href="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2024/MCB/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mcb"/><published>2024-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2024/MCB</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2024/MCB/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Temporal Evolution in Cloud Water Adjustment to Aerosol Perturbations</title><link href="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2024/LES/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Temporal Evolution in Cloud Water Adjustment to Aerosol Perturbations"/><published>2024-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2024/LES</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2024/LES/"><![CDATA[<p>Characterizing the magnitute and evolution of cloud water adjustment to aerosol perturbations is crucial to understand aerosol effects on clouds (i.e., brightening or darkening). Using a large ensemble of (300+) diurnal large-eddy simulations (LES) of marine stratocumulus and a novel conditional Monte Carlo sampling technique, I demonstrated that solar heating as a key factor buffering cloud responses after sunrise, underscoring the importance of timing for aerosol seeding in MCB scenarios. The conditional Monte Carlo sampling approach has the potential to be applied to also observational datasets and GCM Perturbed Parameter Ensembles (PPEs).</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset=" /assets/img/LES_poster-480.webp 480w, /assets/img/LES_poster-800.webp 800w, /assets/img/LES_poster-1400.webp 1400w, " sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/LES_poster.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <hr/> <blockquote> <p>This work not only illustrates a (solar heating) buferring mechanism with direct implications for Marine Cloud Brightening (MCB) proposals, but also demonstrates the usefulness of an innovative conditional Monte Carlo (cMC) sampling technique for testing hypotheses with simulation ensembles (e.g., PPEs).</p> </blockquote> <h4 id="related-publications">Related Publications</h4> <ul> <li> <p><strong>J. Zhang</strong>, Y.-S. Chen, T. Yamaguchi, and G. Feingold (2024): Cloud water adjustments to aerosol perturbations are buffered by solar heating in non-precipitating marine stratocumuli. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 24(18), 10425–10440. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-24-10425-2024"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-24-10425-2024</em></a></p> </li> <li> <p>Y.-S. Chen, <strong>J. Zhang</strong>, F. Hoffmann, T. Yamaguchi, and G. Feingold (2024): Diurnal evolution of non-precipitating marine stratocumuli in a large-eddy simulation ensemble. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 24(22), 12661–12685. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-24-12661-2024"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-24-12661-2024</em></a></p> </li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="research"/><category term="LES-modeling"/><category term="Ensemble-modeling"/><category term="Monte-Carlo-sampling"/><category term="Marine-Cloud-Brightening"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using ensemble of Large-eddy simulations (LES) and a novel conditional Monte Carle sampling method to examine the evolution in cloud water adjustment.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Low-Cloud Albedo Susceptibility to Aerosol Perturbations</title><link href="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2023/susceptibility/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Low-Cloud Albedo Susceptibility to Aerosol Perturbations"/><published>2023-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2023/susceptibility</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2023/susceptibility/"><![CDATA[<p>Characterizing and quantifying aerosol-cloud interactions are fundamental to improving future climate projections and assessing the viability of MCB. In this work, I developed a satellite-based, bottom-up framework for deriving cloud albedo susceptibility that controls for co-varying meteorological factors. This method revealed three distinct, physically-supported susceptibility regimes, their meteorological drivers, and their spatiotemporal variability across marine low-cloud regions.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset=" /assets/img/susceptibility_1slide-480.webp 480w, /assets/img/susceptibility_1slide-800.webp 800w, /assets/img/susceptibility_1slide-1400.webp 1400w, " sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/susceptibility_1slide.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <hr/> <blockquote> <p>The findings stress the importance to consider the co-variability between cloud susceptibility and background aerosol condition in informing strategies for MCB. These findings and the framework are now widely recognized and adopted in the field.</p> </blockquote> <h4 id="related-publications">Related Publications</h4> <ul> <li> <p><strong>J. Zhang</strong> and G. Feingold (2023): Distinct regional meteorological influences on low-cloud albedo susceptibility over global marine stratocumulus regions. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 23(2), 1073–1090. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-23-1073-2023"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-23-1073-2023</em></a></p> </li> <li> <p><strong>J. Zhang</strong>, X. Zhou, T. Goren, and G. Feingold (2022): Albedo susceptibility of northeastern Pacific stratocumulus: the role of covarying meteorological conditions. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 22(2), 861–880. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-22-861-2022"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-22-861-2022</em></a></p> </li> <li> <p>X. Zhou, <strong>J. Zhang</strong>, and G. Feingold (2021): On the importance of sea surface temperature for aerosol-induced brightening of marine clouds and implications for cloud feedback in a future warmer climate. <em>Geophys. Res. Lett.</em>, 48(24), e2021GL095896. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1029/2021GL095896"><em>doi:10.1029/2021GL095896</em></a></p> </li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="research"/><category term="satellite"/><category term="warm-clouds"/><category term="ERA5-reanalysis"/><category term="Marine-Cloud-Brightening"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using satellite snapshot to derive cloud albedo susceptibility to aerosol perturbations for marine stratocumulus clouds.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Impact of Biomass Burning Smoke on Clouds and Climate</title><link href="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2021/smoke/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Impact of Biomass Burning Smoke on Clouds and Climate"/><published>2021-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2021/smoke</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2021/smoke/"><![CDATA[<p>Eastern subtropical oceans are home to warm and bright low-level stratocumulus cloud decks. Among them, the southeast Atlantic basin presents an unique opportunity to study smoke-cloud-radiation interactions where seasonally emitted biomass burning plumes from the southern African continent are being advected over the oceanic region via the southern African Easterly Jet. In this work, I investigated how the presence of biomass burning smoke affects marine boundary layer clouds, particularly in the remote southeast Atlantic region, using field data collected during the DOE LASIC <a href="https://www.arm.gov/research/campaigns/%20amf2016lasic">(Layered Atlantic Smoke Interactions with Clouds)</a> campaign.</p> <blockquote> <p>August is when the highest loading of black carbon is detected within the remote southeast Atlantic boundary layer. I found that the presence of sunlight-absorbing aerosols in the boundary layer suppress cloud water and coverage by modifying the boundary layer’s thermodynamic structure and coupling state throughout the diurnal cycle. In particular, the diurnal-mean liquid water path and low-cloud fraction are reduced when more smoke is present. Observations suggest a decoupling of the boundary layer that continues into the night, helping to trap moisture in the sub-cloud layer. After sunrise, the moisture can ventilate upwards, supporting more vigorous convection. The diurnal cycle is a useful model metric that can ultimately foster skill in simulations of the stratocumulus-to-cumulus transition and low-cloud behavior under future climate scenarios.</p> </blockquote> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset=" /assets/img/Z19-480.webp 480w, /assets/img/Z19-800.webp 800w, /assets/img/Z19-1400.webp 1400w, " sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/Z19.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Schematic of the diurnal cycle for days with 'less' (blue) and 'more' (red) smoke. </div> <hr/> <p>The smoke is primarily in the boundary layer in July-August; then, as the African continent warms, the September-October large-scale circulation encourages more aerosol transport in the free troposphere. Low cloud cover increases climatologically from July to October and becomes more stratiform. Despite similar seasonal cycles in sea surface temperature and large-scale circulation patterns, the monthly-mean southeast Atlantic low-cloud fraction increases more, compared to its counterpart of the southeast Pacific, during austral winter-spring.</p> <blockquote> <p>I found that the combination of changing winds and aerosol transports helps reinforce the July–October evolution in low cloud cover and cloud morphology, compared to conditions with less aerosol present. Representations of the low-cloud seasonal cycle in climate models serve as an indicator of model realism, by comparing with that derived from observations that can then be used as an emergent constraint on the spread in the model equilibrium climate sensitivity (ECS).</p> </blockquote> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset=" /assets/img/Z21-480.webp 480w, /assets/img/Z21-800.webp 800w, /assets/img/Z21-1400.webp 1400w, " sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/Z21.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Amplified seasonal cycle in cloud fraction, cloud type, and all-sky albedo. </div> <hr/> <blockquote> <p>These observationally based findings fill in the temporal dimension of aerosol `semi-direct’ effect and pose a challenging target for both process modeling and GCMs on their representation of aerosols, clouds, and their interactions with atmospheric circulations from diurnal to regional scales.</p> </blockquote> <hr/> <h4 id="related-publications">Related Publications</h4> <ul> <li> <p><strong>J. Zhang</strong> and P. Zuidema (2019): The diurnal cycle of the smoky marine boundary layer observed during August in the remote southeast Atlantic. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 19(23), 14493–14516. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-19-14493-2019"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-19-14493-2019</em></a> <a href="#">(ACP highligh article)</a> <i class="far fa-star"></i></p> </li> <li> <p><strong>J. Zhang</strong> and P. Zuidema (2021): Sunlight-absorbing aerosol amplifies the seasonal cycle in low-cloud fraction over the southeast Atlantic. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 21(14), 11179–11199. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-21-11179-2021"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-21-11179-2021</em></a></p> </li> <li> <p>P. Zuidema, A. Sedlacek III, C. Flynn, S. Springston et al. including <strong>J. Zhang</strong> (2018): The Ascension Island boundary layer in the remote southeast Atlantic is often smoky. <em>Geophys. Res. Lett.</em>, 45(9), 4456–4465. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/2017GL076926"><em>doi:10.1002/2017GL076926</em></a></p> </li> <li> <p>S. Abel, P. Barrett, P. Zuidema, <strong>J. Zhang</strong> et al. (2020): Open cells exhibit weaker entrainment of free-tropospheric biomass-burning aerosol into the south-east Atlantic boundary layer. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 20(7), 4059–4084. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-20-4059-2020"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-20-4059-2020</em></a></p> </li> <li> <p>P. Barrett, S. Abel, H. Coe, et al. including <strong>J. Zhang</strong> (2022): Intercomparison of airborne and surface-based measurements during the CLARIFY, ORACLES and LASIC field experiments. <em>Atmos. Meas. Tech.</em>, 15(21), 6329–6371. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/amt-15-6329-2022"><em>doi:10.5194/amt-15-6329-2022</em></a></p> </li> <li> <p>M. Diamond, P. Saide, P. Zuidema, et al. including <strong>J. Zhang</strong> (2022): Cloud adjustments from large-scale smoke–circulation interactions strongly modulate the southeastern Atlantic stratocumulus-to-cumulus transition. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 22(18), 12113–12151. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-22-12113-2022"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-22-12113-2022</em></a> <a href="#">(ACP highligh article)</a> <i class="far fa-star"></i></p> </li> <li> <p>C. Howes, P. Saide, H. Coe, et al. including <strong>J. Zhang</strong> (2023): Biomass-burning smoke’s properties and its interactions with marine stratocumulus clouds in WRF-CAM5 and southeastern Atlantic field campaigns. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 23(21), 13911–13945. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-23-13911-2023"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-23-13911-2023</em></a></p> </li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="research"/><category term="ground-based"/><category term="satellite"/><category term="ERA5-reanalysis"/><category term="smoke-cloud-interactions"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using field campaign data and satellite observations to characterize how sunlight-absorbing aerosols affect marine stratocumulus clouds.]]></summary></entry></feed>