<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://jianhao1991.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://jianhao1991.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-10-05T05:37:51+00:00</updated><id>https://jianhao1991.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Jianhao Zhang | Research Scientist | CIRES at University of Colorado Boulder &amp; NOAA CSL. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Temporal Evolution in Cloud Water Adjustment to Aerosol Perturbations</title><link href="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2024/LES/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Temporal Evolution in Cloud Water Adjustment to Aerosol Perturbations"/><published>2024-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2024/LES</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2024/LES/"><![CDATA[<p>Characterizing the magnitute and evolution of cloud water adjustment to aerosol perturbations is crucial to understand aerosol effects on clouds (i.e., brightening or darkening). Using a large ensemble of (300+) diurnal large-eddy simulations (LES) of marine stratocumulus and a novel conditional Monte Carlo sampling technique, I demonstrated that solar heating as a key factor buffering cloud responses after sunrise, underscoring the importance of timing for aerosol seeding in MCB scenarios. The conditional Monte Carlo sampling approach has the potential to be applied to also observational datasets and GCM Perturbed Parameter Ensembles (PPEs).</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset=" /assets/img/Z24.1-480.webp 480w, /assets/img/Z24.1-800.webp 800w, /assets/img/Z24.1-1400.webp 1400w, " sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/Z24.1.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset=" /assets/img/Z24.3-480.webp 480w, /assets/img/Z24.3-800.webp 800w, /assets/img/Z24.3-1400.webp 1400w, " sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/Z24.3.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> [LEFT] Diurnal cycle of the N<sub>d</sub>–LWP regression slope, separated by colors representing different values at sunrise (large dots). Mean values of the 50 times, 25-member conditional Monte Carlo subsampling approach are shown. [RIGHT] Diurnal cycle of the N<sub>d</sub>–SW<sub>reflected</sub> regression slope, separated by colors representing aerosol perturbations ("seeding") at different times before sunrise. </div> <hr/> <blockquote> <p>This work not only illustrates a (solar heating) buferring mechanism with direct implications for Marine Cloud Brightening (MCB) proposals, but also demonstrates the usefulness of an innovative conditional Monte Carlo (cMC) sampling technique for testing hypotheses with simulation ensembles (e.g., PPEs).</p> </blockquote> <h4 id="related-publications">Related Publications</h4> <ul> <li> <p><strong>J. Zhang</strong>, Y.-S. Chen, T. Yamaguchi, and G. Feingold (2024): Cloud water adjustments to aerosol perturbations are buffered by solar heating in non-precipitating marine stratocumuli. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 24(18), 10425–10440. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-24-10425-2024"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-24-10425-2024</em></a></p> </li> <li> <p>Y.-S. Chen, <strong>J. Zhang</strong>, F. Hoffmann, T. Yamaguchi, and G. Feingold (2024): Diurnal evolution of non-precipitating marine stratocumuli in a large-eddy simulation ensemble. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 24(22), 12661–12685. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-24-12661-2024"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-24-12661-2024</em></a></p> </li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="research"/><category term="LES-modeling"/><category term="Monte-Carlo-sampling"/><category term="Marine-Cloud-Brightening"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using ensemble Large-eddy simulations (LES) and a novel conditional Monte Carle sampling method to examine the evolution in cloud water adjustment.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Low-Cloud Albedo Susceptibility to Aerosol Perturbations</title><link href="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2023/susceptibility/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Low-Cloud Albedo Susceptibility to Aerosol Perturbations"/><published>2023-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2023/susceptibility</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2023/susceptibility/"><![CDATA[<p>Characterizing and quantifying aerosol-cloud interactions are fundamental to improving future climate projections and assessing the viability of MCB. In this work, I developed a satellite-based, bottom-up framework for deriving cloud albedo susceptibility that controls for co-varying meteorological factors. This method revealed three distinct, physically-supported susceptibility regimes, their meteorological drivers, and their spatiotemporal variability across marine low-cloud regions.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset=" /assets/img/Z22_L_N-480.webp 480w, /assets/img/Z22_L_N-800.webp 800w, /assets/img/Z22_L_N-1400.webp 1400w, " sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/Z22_L_N.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset=" /assets/img/Z23_spider-480.webp 480w, /assets/img/Z23_spider-800.webp 800w, /assets/img/Z23_spider-1400.webp 1400w, " sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/Z23_spider.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> [LEFT]Cloud albedo susceptibility (colored filled circles) in LWP–N<sub>d</sub> space for the NE Pacific stratocumulus deck. Size of the filled circles indicates the relative frequency of occurrence. Three susceptibility regimes are identified: (i) precipitating–brightening (light green; positive susceptibility states with effective radii greater than 12µm), (ii) entrainment–darkening (brown; negative susceptibility states and right-hand side of the EEF isoline), and (iii) Twomey–brightening (dark green; non-precipitating states with positive susceptibilities) regimes. [RIGHT] Monthly mean albedo susceptibility, overlaid with monthly mean low-cloud frequency of occurrence and cloud droplet number concentration. </div> <hr/> <blockquote> <p>The findings stress the importance to consider the co-variability between cloud susceptibility and background aerosol condition in informing strategies for MCB. These findings and the framework are now widely recognized and adopted in the field.</p> </blockquote> <h4 id="related-publications">Related Publications</h4> <ul> <li> <p><strong>J. Zhang</strong> and G. Feingold (2023): Distinct regional meteorological influences on low-cloud albedo susceptibility over global marine stratocumulus regions. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 23(2), 1073–1090. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-23-1073-2023"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-23-1073-2023</em></a></p> </li> <li> <p><strong>J. Zhang</strong>, X. Zhou, T. Goren, and G. Feingold (2022): Albedo susceptibility of northeastern Pacific stratocumulus: the role of covarying meteorological conditions. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 22(2), 861–880. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-22-861-2022"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-22-861-2022</em></a></p> </li> <li> <p>X. Zhou, <strong>J. Zhang</strong>, and G. Feingold (2021): On the importance of sea surface temperature for aerosol-induced brightening of marine clouds and implications for cloud feedback in a future warmer climate. <em>Geophys. Res. Lett.</em>, 48(24), e2021GL095896. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1029/2021GL095896"><em>doi:10.1029/2021GL095896</em></a></p> </li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="research"/><category term="satellite"/><category term="warm-clouds"/><category term="ERA5-reanalysis"/><category term="Marine-Cloud-Brightening"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using satellite snapshot to derive cloud albedo susceptibility to aerosol perturbations for marine stratocumulus clouds.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Impact of Biomass Burning Smoke on Clouds and Climate</title><link href="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2022/smoke/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Impact of Biomass Burning Smoke on Clouds and Climate"/><published>2022-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2022/smoke</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2022/smoke/"><![CDATA[<p>Eastern subtropical oceans are home to warm and bright low-level stratocumulus cloud decks. Among them, the southeast Atlantic basin presents an unique opportunity to study smoke-cloud-radiation interactions where seasonally emitted biomass burning plumes from the southern African continent are being advected over the oceanic region via the southern African Easterly Jet. In this work, I investigated how the presence of biomass burning smoke affects marine boundary layer clouds, particularly in the remote southeast Atlantic region. I demonstrated that the presence of sunlight-absorbing aerosols in the boundary layer suppress cloud water and coverage by modifying the boundary layer’s thermodynamic structure and coupling state throughout the diurnal cycle.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset=" /assets/img/Z19-480.webp 480w, /assets/img/Z19-800.webp 800w, /assets/img/Z19-1400.webp 1400w, " sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/Z19.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Schematic of the diurnal cycle for days with 'less' (blue) and 'more' (red) smoke. </div> <p>The seasonal variation in the vertical distribution of smoke contributes to the amplification of the seasonal cycle in low-cloud fraction, with significant implications for regional climate dynamics and radiative effects.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset=" /assets/img/Z21-480.webp 480w, /assets/img/Z21-800.webp 800w, /assets/img/Z21-1400.webp 1400w, " sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/Z21.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Amplified seasonal cycle in cloud fraction, cloud type, and all-sky albedo. </div> <hr/> <blockquote> <p>These observationally based findings fill in the temporal dimension of aerosol `semi-direct’ effect and pose a challenging target for both process modeling and GCMs on their representation of aerosols, clouds, and their interactions with atmospheric circulations from diurnal to regional scales.</p> </blockquote> <h4 id="related-publications">Related Publications</h4> <ul> <li> <p><strong>J. Zhang</strong> and P. Zuidema (2019): The diurnal cycle of the smoky marine boundary layer observed during August in the remote southeast Atlantic. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 19(23), 14493–14516. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-19-14493-2019"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-19-14493-2019</em></a> <a href="#">(ACP highligh article)</a> <i class="far fa-star"></i></p> </li> <li> <p><strong>J. Zhang</strong> and P. Zuidema (2021): Sunlight-absorbing aerosol amplifies the seasonal cycle in low-cloud fraction over the southeast Atlantic. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 21(14), 11179–11199. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-21-11179-2021"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-21-11179-2021</em></a></p> </li> <li> <p>P. Zuidema, A. Sedlacek III, C. Flynn, S. Springston et al. including <strong>J. Zhang</strong> (2018): The Ascension Island boundary layer in the remote southeast Atlantic is often smoky. <em>Geophys. Res. Lett.</em>, 45(9), 4456–4465. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/2017GL076926"><em>doi:10.1002/2017GL076926</em></a></p> </li> <li> <p>S. Abel, P. Barrett, P. Zuidema, <strong>J. Zhang</strong> et al. (2020): Open cells exhibit weaker entrainment of free-tropospheric biomass-burning aerosol into the south-east Atlantic boundary layer. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 20(7), 4059–4084. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-20-4059-2020"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-20-4059-2020</em></a></p> </li> <li> <p>P. Barrett, S. Abel, H. Coe, et al. including <strong>J. Zhang</strong> (2022): Intercomparison of airborne and surface-based measurements during the CLARIFY, ORACLES and LASIC field experiments. <em>Atmos. Meas. Tech.</em>, 15(21), 6329–6371. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/amt-15-6329-2022"><em>doi:10.5194/amt-15-6329-2022</em></a></p> </li> <li> <p>M. Diamond, P. Saide, P. Zuidema, et al. including <strong>J. Zhang</strong> (2022): Cloud adjustments from large-scale smoke–circulation interactions strongly modulate the southeastern Atlantic stratocumulus-to-cumulus transition. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 22(18), 12113–12151. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-22-12113-2022"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-22-12113-2022</em></a> <a href="#">(ACP highligh article)</a> <i class="far fa-star"></i></p> </li> <li> <p>C. Howes, P. Saide, H. Coe, et al. including <strong>J. Zhang</strong> (2023): Biomass-burning smoke’s properties and its interactions with marine stratocumulus clouds in WRF-CAM5 and southeastern Atlantic field campaigns. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 23(21), 13911–13945. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-23-13911-2023"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-23-13911-2023</em></a></p> </li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="research"/><category term="ground-based"/><category term="satellite"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using LASIC field campaign data to characterize how does sunlight-absorbing aerosols affect marine stratocumulus clouds]]></summary></entry></feed>