<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://jianhao1991.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://jianhao1991.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-10-06T21:26:05+00:00</updated><id>https://jianhao1991.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Jianhao Zhang | Research Scientist | CIRES at University of Colorado Boulder &amp; NOAA CSL. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Radiative Impact of the IMO2020 Shipping Fuel Regulation</title><link href="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2025/IMO/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radiative Impact of the IMO2020 Shipping Fuel Regulation"/><published>2025-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2025/IMO</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2025/IMO/"><![CDATA[<p>Ship tracks—bright, linear clouds trailing ocean-going ships—are striking manifestations of cloud adjustment in response to inadvertent aerosol perturbations from shipping emissions. Their radiative characteristics, contrasted with surrounding unperturbed scenes, offer invaluable insights into aerosol–cloud–radiation interactions. In 2020, new fuel regulations were implemented in the shipping sector, limiting sulfur emissions from ships across the world’s oceans. While reducing this atmospheric pollutant improves air quality, the change has complex and unintended consequences for global warming.</p> <blockquote> <p><strong><em>The Science</em></strong> In this work, I trained ensembles of neural networks to examine how reduced pollution from shipping affects cloud properties and climate. The results reveal that while the IMO2020 regulation brings significant environmental and public health benefits, it also produces a global warming effect of approximately 0.1 W m<sup>−2</sup>, equivalent to about 3.5 years of CO<sub>2</sub> warming. We concluded that even this substantial, abrupt radiative forcing is challenging to detect, underscoring the difficulty of observing real-world cloud adjustments against natural cloud variability. Regionally, detectability is higher for the southeastern Atlantic stratocumulus deck.</p> </blockquote> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset=" /assets/img/IMO_poster-480.webp 480w, /assets/img/IMO_poster-800.webp 800w, /assets/img/IMO_poster-1400.webp 1400w, " sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/IMO_poster.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <blockquote> <p><strong><em>The Impact</em></strong> This study raises concerns that future reductions in aerosol emissions will accelerate warming and that proposed deliberate aerosol perturbations such as marine cloud brightening will need to be substantial in order to overcome the low detectability.</p> </blockquote> <hr/> <h4 id="related-publications">Related Publications</h4> <ul> <li><strong>J. Zhang</strong>, Y.-S. Chen, E. Gryspeerdt, T. Yamaguchi, and G. Feingold (2025): Radiative forcing from the 2020 shipping fuel regulation is large but hard to detect. <em>Commun. Earth Environ.</em>, 6(18), 1–11. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s43247-024-01911-9"><em>doi:10.1038/s43247-024-01911-9</em></a></li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="research"/><category term="Machine-Learning"/><category term="Neural-Networks"/><category term="Marine-Cloud-Brightening"/><category term="Detectability"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using ensembles of neural networks trained on satellite and reanalysis to quantify the radiative impact of the 2020 global shipping fuel sulfur regulation (IMO2020).]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Physical Science Reseach for Marine Cloud Brightening</title><link href="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2024/MCB/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Physical Science Reseach for Marine Cloud Brightening"/><published>2024-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2024/MCB</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2024/MCB/"><![CDATA[<p>As evidence for severe impacts of global warming continues to accumulate, the possibility of averting the worst effects of climate change through climate intervention (CI) is a topic of increasing scrutiny and debate. The common goal of these CI proposals is to cool the climate by deliberately modifying the solar (shortwave) or terrestrial (longwave) radiation pathways in the Earth’s atmosphere, aiming to reduce the worst impacts of rising global temperatures, in addition to reducing greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions. Marine Cloud Brightening (MCB), one such CI proposal, focuses on enhancing the reflection of solar by warm (liquid containing) marine clouds through the deliberate injection of sea salt particles into these clouds.</p> <blockquote> <p><strong><em>The Overview</em></strong> Our papers lay out existing physical science knowledge and gaps on MCB and discuss research needed to assess the viability and risks of MCB.</p> </blockquote> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset=" /assets/img/F24-480.webp 480w, /assets/img/F24-800.webp 800w, /assets/img/F24-1400.webp 1400w, " sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/F24.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Marine cloud brightening proposals use ship-based generators to release haze droplets. In optimal conditions, these droplets are lofted into clouds by updrafts, modifying cloud microphysics by increasing droplet concentrations, suppressing rain formation, and extending cloud coverage and lifetime. The left side illustrates key aerosol, cloud, dynamics, and radiation processes in the marine boundary layer that underpin MCB in shallow liquid clouds. The strong coupling between these processes presents challenges and opportunities for understanding the effects of seawater haze injections. Figure is reproduced from [Feingold et al. 2024 Science Advances](https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adi8594). </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset=" /assets/img/F24.2-480.webp 480w, /assets/img/F24.2-800.webp 800w, /assets/img/F24.2-1400.webp 1400w, " sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/F24.2.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> An integrated view of MCB research. Laboratory facilities such as cloud chambers, together with observations at various scales, help improve the representation of physical processes in models. Parcel models, large eddy models, and cloud-resolving models inform global model activities to enhance the reliability of regional climate responses. The Earth view image is courtesy of the European Organisation for the Exploitation of Meteorological Satellites (EUMETSAT). Figure courtesy of Chelsea Thompson, NOAA/CSL. </div> <hr/> <h4 id="related-publications">Related Publications</h4> <ul> <li> <p><strong>J. Zhang</strong> and G. Feingold (2024): Physical Science of Marine Cloud Brightening: Knowledge and Gaps, in Topical Group on the Physics of Climate, American Physical Society, October 2024, pp. 1–4. <a href="https://engage.aps.org/gpc/resources/newsletters">(invited article)</a></p> </li> <li> <p>G. Feingold, V. Ghate, L. Russell, et al. including <strong>J. Zhang</strong> (2024): Physical science research needed to evaluate the viability and risks of marine cloud brightening. <em>Sci. Adv.</em>, 10(12), eadi8594. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adi8594"><em>doi:10.1126/sciadv.adi8594</em></a></p> </li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="overview"/><category term="Marine-Cloud-Brightening"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Overviewing the physical science basis for MCB and discussing the knowledge and gaps in MCB viability and the risks associated with it.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Temporal Evolution in Cloud Water Adjustment to Aerosol Perturbations</title><link href="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2024/LES/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Temporal Evolution in Cloud Water Adjustment to Aerosol Perturbations"/><published>2024-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2024/LES</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2024/LES/"><![CDATA[<p>Marine low-level clouds are key to the Earth’s energy budget due to their expansive coverage over global oceans and their high reflectance of incoming solar radiation. Their responses to anthropogenic aerosol perturbations remain the largest source of uncertainty in estimating the anthropogenic radiative forcing of climate. A major challenge is the quantification of the cloud water response to aerosol perturbations. In particular, the presence of feedbacks through microphysical, dynamical, and thermodynamical pathways at various spatial and temporal scales could augment or weaken the response. Central to this problem is the temporal evolution in cloud adjustment, governed by entangled feedback mechanisms. Using a large ensemble of (300+) diurnal large-eddy simulations (LES) of marine stratocumulus and a novel conditional Monte Carlo sampling technique, I demonstrate that solar heating as a key factor buffering cloud responses after sunrise, underscoring the importance of timing for aerosol seeding in MCB scenarios.</p> <blockquote> <p><strong><em>The Science</em></strong> I apply an innovative conditional Monte Carlo subsampling approach to a large ensemble of diurnal large-eddy simulation of non-precipitating marine stratocumulus. I find a persistent negative trend in this relationship at night, confirming that the role of microphysically enhanced cloud-top entrainment. After sunrise, the evolution in this relationship appears buffered and converges to ~-0.2 in the late afternoon. This buffering effect is attributed to a strong dependence of cloud-layer shortwave absorption on cloud liquid water path. These diurnal cycle characteristics further demonstrate a tight connection between cloud brightening potential and the relationship between cloud water and droplet number at sunrise, which has implications for the impact of the timing of advertent aerosol perturbations.</p> </blockquote> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset=" /assets/img/LES_poster-480.webp 480w, /assets/img/LES_poster-800.webp 800w, /assets/img/LES_poster-1400.webp 1400w, " sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/LES_poster.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <blockquote> <p><strong><em>The Impact</em></strong> This study underscores the critical role of solar heating in modulating cloud responses, acting as a buffering mechanism with direct implications to Marine Cloud Brightening (MCB) strategies. Furthermore, the conditional Monte Carlo sampling framework introduced here could be readily extended to observational datasets and General Circulation Model (GCM) Perturbed Parameter Ensembles (PPEs).</p> </blockquote> <hr/> <h4 id="related-publications">Related Publications</h4> <ul> <li> <p><strong>J. Zhang</strong>, Y.-S. Chen, T. Yamaguchi, and G. Feingold (2024): Cloud water adjustments to aerosol perturbations are buffered by solar heating in non-precipitating marine stratocumuli. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 24(18), 10425–10440. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-24-10425-2024"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-24-10425-2024</em></a></p> </li> <li> <p>Y.-S. Chen, <strong>J. Zhang</strong>, F. Hoffmann, T. Yamaguchi, and G. Feingold (2024): Diurnal evolution of non-precipitating marine stratocumuli in a large-eddy simulation ensemble. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 24(22), 12661–12685. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-24-12661-2024"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-24-12661-2024</em></a></p> </li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="research"/><category term="LES-modeling"/><category term="Ensemble-modeling"/><category term="Monte-Carlo-sampling"/><category term="Marine-Cloud-Brightening"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using ensemble of Large-eddy simulations (LES) and a novel conditional Monte Carle sampling method to examine temporal evolution in cloud water adjustment.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Low-Cloud Albedo Susceptibility to Aerosol Perturbations</title><link href="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2023/susceptibility/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Low-Cloud Albedo Susceptibility to Aerosol Perturbations"/><published>2023-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2023/susceptibility</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2023/susceptibility/"><![CDATA[<p>Characterizing and quantifying aerosol-cloud interactions are fundamental to improving future climate projections and assessing the viability of MCB. In this work, I developed a satellite-based, bottom-up framework for deriving cloud albedo susceptibility that controls for co-varying meteorological factors. This method revealed three distinct, physically-supported susceptibility regimes, their meteorological drivers, and their spatiotemporal variability across marine low-cloud regions.</p> <blockquote> <p><strong><em>The Science</em></strong> The sensitivity of cloud brightness (ability to cool the Earth through reflecting sunlight) to the amount of aerosol (tiny particles in the atmosphere) in the marine boundary layer is quantified using spaceborne observations of clouds and radiation. When clouds are sorted by their amount of water condensate and number of droplets, cloud regimes emerge, distinguished by their potential to be brightened or darkened in response to an aerosol perturbation. These regimes include (i) thin non-precipitating clouds that exhibit brightening, where the Twomey effect is expected to dominate; (ii) thicker non-precipitating clouds that exhibit darkening, where microphysically driven entrainment feedbacks are expected to be the most active; and (iii) mostly precipitating clouds that exhibit brightening, consistent with the precipitation-suppression mechanism due to reduced drop sizes.</p> </blockquote> <blockquote> <p>We find that this regime manifestation in the LWP-Nd space is robust across different subtropical ocean basins where marine stratocumuli prevail. We further demonstrate that the covariation among synoptic scale environmental conditions dictates how clouds populate each regime, leading to regionally distinct evolutions in cloud brightness sensitivity to aerosol changes.</p> </blockquote> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset=" /assets/img/susceptibility_1slide-480.webp 480w, /assets/img/susceptibility_1slide-800.webp 800w, /assets/img/susceptibility_1slide-1400.webp 1400w, " sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/susceptibility_1slide.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <blockquote> <p><strong><em>The Impact</em></strong> Marine low-level liquid-form clouds cool the Earth effectively by reflecting a good fraction of sunlight that would otherwise be absorbed by the dark ocean. New insights provided by a bottom-up assessment of cloud albedo susceptibility based on satellite observations confront the long-standing impression that more aerosol leads to brighter clouds, the foundation of one of the proposed climate intervention approaches, namely Marine Cloud Brightening (MCB). We demonstrate that under certain meteorological conditions, especially under deep boundary layers and warm SST, clouds can be darkened due to loss of water condensate through enhanced droplet evaporation. Our work stresses the importance of accounting for meteorology-aerosol covariations when assessing the viability of MCB and scaling up local-to-global cloud radiative response to aerosol perturbations. These findings and the assessment approach are now widely recognized and adopted in the field.</p> </blockquote> <hr/> <h4 id="related-publications">Related Publications</h4> <ul> <li> <p><strong>J. Zhang</strong> and G. Feingold (2023): Distinct regional meteorological influences on low-cloud albedo susceptibility over global marine stratocumulus regions. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 23(2), 1073–1090. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-23-1073-2023"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-23-1073-2023</em></a></p> </li> <li> <p><strong>J. Zhang</strong>, X. Zhou, T. Goren, and G. Feingold (2022): Albedo susceptibility of northeastern Pacific stratocumulus: the role of covarying meteorological conditions. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 22(2), 861–880. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-22-861-2022"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-22-861-2022</em></a></p> </li> <li> <p>X. Zhou, <strong>J. Zhang</strong>, and G. Feingold (2021): On the importance of sea surface temperature for aerosol-induced brightening of marine clouds and implications for cloud feedback in a future warmer climate. <em>Geophys. Res. Lett.</em>, 48(24), e2021GL095896. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1029/2021GL095896"><em>doi:10.1029/2021GL095896</em></a></p> </li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="research"/><category term="satellite"/><category term="ERA5-reanalysis"/><category term="Marine-Cloud-Brightening"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using satellite snapshot to derive albedo susceptibility for marine stratocumulus clouds and explore its co-variability with large-scale meteorological conditions.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Impact of Biomass Burning Smoke on Clouds and Climate</title><link href="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2021/smoke/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Impact of Biomass Burning Smoke on Clouds and Climate"/><published>2021-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2021/smoke</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jianhao1991.github.io/blog/2021/smoke/"><![CDATA[<p>Eastern subtropical oceans are home to warm and bright low-level stratocumulus cloud decks. Among them, the southeast Atlantic basin presents an unique opportunity to study smoke-cloud-radiation interactions where seasonally emitted biomass burning plumes from the southern African continent are being advected over the oceanic region via the southern African Easterly Jet. In this work, I investigated how the presence of biomass burning smoke affects marine boundary layer clouds, particularly in the remote southeast Atlantic region, using field data collected during the DOE LASIC <a href="https://www.arm.gov/research/campaigns/%20amf2016lasic">(Layered Atlantic Smoke Interactions with Clouds)</a> campaign.</p> <blockquote> <p><strong><em>The Science</em></strong> August is when the highest loading of black carbon is detected within the remote southeast Atlantic boundary layer. I find that the presence of sunlight-absorbing aerosols in the boundary layer suppress cloud water and coverage by modifying the boundary layer’s thermodynamic structure and coupling state throughout the diurnal cycle. In particular, the diurnal-mean liquid water path and low-cloud fraction are reduced when more smoke is present. Observations suggest a decoupling of the boundary layer that continues into the night, helping to trap moisture in the sub-cloud layer. After sunrise, the moisture can ventilate upwards, supporting more vigorous convection. The diurnal cycle is a useful model metric that can ultimately foster skill in simulations of the stratocumulus-to-cumulus transition and low-cloud behavior under future climate scenarios.</p> </blockquote> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset=" /assets/img/Z19-480.webp 480w, /assets/img/Z19-800.webp 800w, /assets/img/Z19-1400.webp 1400w, " sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/Z19.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Schematic of the diurnal cycle for days with 'less' (blue) and 'more' (red) smoke. </div> <hr/> <blockquote> <p>The smoke is primarily in the boundary layer in July-August; then, as the African continent warms, the September-October large-scale circulation encourages more aerosol transport in the free troposphere. Low cloud cover increases climatologically from July to October and becomes more stratiform. Despite similar seasonal cycles in sea surface temperature and large-scale circulation patterns, the monthly-mean southeast Atlantic low-cloud fraction increases more, compared to its counterpart of the southeast Pacific, during austral winter-spring.</p> </blockquote> <blockquote> <p>I find that the combination of changing winds and aerosol transports helps reinforce the July–October evolution in low cloud cover and cloud morphology, compared to conditions with less aerosol present. Representations of the low-cloud seasonal cycle in climate models serve as an indicator of model realism, by comparing with that derived from observations that can then be used as an emergent constraint on the spread in the model equilibrium climate sensitivity (ECS).</p> </blockquote> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset=" /assets/img/Z21-480.webp 480w, /assets/img/Z21-800.webp 800w, /assets/img/Z21-1400.webp 1400w, " sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/Z21.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Amplified seasonal cycle in cloud fraction, cloud type, and all-sky albedo. </div> <hr/> <blockquote> <p><strong><em>The Impact</em></strong> These observationally based findings fill in the temporal dimension of aerosol `semi-direct’ effect and pose a challenging target for both process modeling and GCMs on their representation of aerosols, clouds, and their interactions with atmospheric circulations from diurnal to regional scales.</p> </blockquote> <hr/> <h4 id="related-publications">Related Publications</h4> <ul> <li> <p><strong>J. Zhang</strong> and P. Zuidema (2019): The diurnal cycle of the smoky marine boundary layer observed during August in the remote southeast Atlantic. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 19(23), 14493–14516. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-19-14493-2019"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-19-14493-2019</em></a> <a href="#">(ACP highligh article)</a> <i class="far fa-star"></i></p> </li> <li> <p><strong>J. Zhang</strong> and P. Zuidema (2021): Sunlight-absorbing aerosol amplifies the seasonal cycle in low-cloud fraction over the southeast Atlantic. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 21(14), 11179–11199. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-21-11179-2021"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-21-11179-2021</em></a></p> </li> <li> <p>P. Zuidema, A. Sedlacek III, C. Flynn, S. Springston et al. including <strong>J. Zhang</strong> (2018): The Ascension Island boundary layer in the remote southeast Atlantic is often smoky. <em>Geophys. Res. Lett.</em>, 45(9), 4456–4465. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/2017GL076926"><em>doi:10.1002/2017GL076926</em></a></p> </li> <li> <p>S. Abel, P. Barrett, P. Zuidema, <strong>J. Zhang</strong> et al. (2020): Open cells exhibit weaker entrainment of free-tropospheric biomass-burning aerosol into the south-east Atlantic boundary layer. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 20(7), 4059–4084. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-20-4059-2020"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-20-4059-2020</em></a></p> </li> <li> <p>P. Barrett, S. Abel, H. Coe, et al. including <strong>J. Zhang</strong> (2022): Intercomparison of airborne and surface-based measurements during the CLARIFY, ORACLES and LASIC field experiments. <em>Atmos. Meas. Tech.</em>, 15(21), 6329–6371. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/amt-15-6329-2022"><em>doi:10.5194/amt-15-6329-2022</em></a></p> </li> <li> <p>M. Diamond, P. Saide, P. Zuidema, et al. including <strong>J. Zhang</strong> (2022): Cloud adjustments from large-scale smoke–circulation interactions strongly modulate the southeastern Atlantic stratocumulus-to-cumulus transition. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 22(18), 12113–12151. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-22-12113-2022"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-22-12113-2022</em></a> <a href="#">(ACP highligh article)</a> <i class="far fa-star"></i></p> </li> <li> <p>C. Howes, P. Saide, H. Coe, et al. including <strong>J. Zhang</strong> (2023): Biomass-burning smoke’s properties and its interactions with marine stratocumulus clouds in WRF-CAM5 and southeastern Atlantic field campaigns. <em>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</em>, 23(21), 13911–13945. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-23-13911-2023"><em>doi:10.5194/acp-23-13911-2023</em></a></p> </li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="research"/><category term="ground-based"/><category term="satellite"/><category term="ERA5-reanalysis"/><category term="smoke-cloud-interactions"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using field campaign data and satellite observations to characterize how sunlight-absorbing aerosols affect marine stratocumulus clouds.]]></summary></entry></feed>